<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtual Machines on Craig Forrester</title>
    <link>https://www.craigforrester.com/tags/virtual-machines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virtual Machines on Craig Forrester</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 16:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.craigforrester.com/tags/virtual-machines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resize Azure Virtual Machine Disks with Azure PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://www.craigforrester.com/posts/resize-azure-vm-disks-with-azure-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigforrester.com/posts/resize-azure-vm-disks-with-azure-powershell/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk through how to expand a managed OS disk on an Azure virtual machine with PowerShell. In the previous post in this series, we covered how to achieve this with Azure CLI in Bash, and in later posts, we will cover how to convert these commands into scripts.
Log In and Verify Subscription Before we do anything, as always, we want to be certain we have PowerShell connected to Azure Resource Manager, and that we are on the correct subscription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resize Azure Virtual Machine Disks with Azure CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.craigforrester.com/posts/resize-azure-vm-disks-with-azure-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.craigforrester.com/posts/resize-azure-vm-disks-with-azure-cli/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk through how to expand a managed OS disk on an Azure virtual machine. In subsequent posts, we will cover how to convert this into a script for use interactively or with automation tools.
Log In and Verify Subscription I always like to include a reminder to validate that you are logged in to the correct Azure Subscription. For those of us with multiple clients and subscriptions to manage, failure to do this can have serious consequences, so I suggest do so every time, and building some kind of verification logic into your automation scripts as well, where it makes sense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>